-我什么都没说  -别说话了
- I didn't say anything. - Stop talking.
你这也是在说话
That's talking.
你觉得她睡着了吗
You think she's asleep yet?
我和你一样都在门外啊
I'm on the same side of the door as you are.
-别说话了  -小卡
- Stop talking. - Cam.
莉莉今天掉了第一颗牙
Lily lost her first tooth today.
她现在非常期待牙仙子的到访
And she's very excited about the visit from the tooth fairy.
我第一次有牙齿松动时
When I have my first loose tooth,
我妈将绳子一端系在那颗牙上
my mom tied one end of the string to it,
另一端系在奶牛的尾巴上
the other to the tail of a cow
用12号猎枪开了一枪
fired off a 12-gauge shotgun,
奶牛跑出了房间
and the cow went running out of the room.
本故事纯属虚构
That never happened.
你去看看我卧室里的奶牛型墙洞再说
Tell that to the cow-shaped hole in my bedroom wall.
抓住了
Gotcha!
你们跑我房里来干嘛
what are you doing here?
你们又不是牙仙子
You're not the tooth fairy.
不  我们就是想来看看她来了没
N-no. But we just wanted to see if she'd come yet.
没呢  看来她真的一点都不着急
No. She sure is taking her sweet time.
-也许你该继续睡觉  亲爱的  -对
- Maybe you should just go back to sleep, sweetie. - Yeah.
因为可能还要再等一会儿
'cause it could take a while.
我时间多的是
I've got nowhere to be.
妈  我今天不能迟到
Mom, I can't be late today.
桑杰·帕特尔和我要解剖一头猪
Sanjay Patel and I are dissecting a pig.
你这辈子所谓的约会真可悲啊
So sad what passes for a date in your life.
-海莉  -他老是让我拿工具给他
- Haley. - He keeps asking me to hand him all of the instruments.
他想让我扮演护士的角色
He wants me to act like a nurse.
那听起来像是海莉的约会
Now it sounds like a date in Haley's life.
在你说"不行"之前
Okay, before you say no...
-不行  -你连看都没看呢
- No. - You haven't even seen it yet.
我还是要说不行
Mm, I'm sticking with "No."
这是为卢克的职业日准备的
It's for Luke's Career Day.
我想我可以让孩子们尝试
I thought I'd offer the kids a chance
把脸放在我的身体上
to put their face on my body.
我也刚意识到很变态
I just heard it, too.
你们怎么从来没办过职业日
How come you guys never had a Career Day?
-经费削减  -东北大风暴停课
- Cutbacks. - Nor'easter.
今天我要讲述我的一生挚爱
Today I get to talk about the love of my life...
住宅房地产
residential real estate.
他真是意识不到自己在说什么
He really doesn't hear it.
我要让卢克感到骄傲
I wanna make Luke proud.
我要成为他的英雄
I wanna be his hero like my dad was
就像以前我父亲向我的同学们
when he talked to my class
讲述开杂货店的故事时那样
about running a grocery store.
他拿着两把带皮套的价格标枪进屋
He came in with two price guns in holsters
在我们的老师还没反应过来时
and marked our teacher at $1.29
给她打了个1.29刀的标签
before she knew what hit her.
我敢说那肯定"很好笑"
I bet that produced a lot of laughs.
克莱尔  拜托
Claire, please.
奥利维亚·伯曼的妈妈
And Olivia Berman's mom
在图书馆的珍本书部工作
works in the rare books department at the library.
真希望我有机会去向她讨教讨教
Hope I get a chance to pick that brain.
看来你们的职业日已经排得满满当当了
Looks like you got quite the Career Day lineup.
我猜他们已经邀请到搞衣柜的人了吧
So I guess they already got a closet guy coming in, huh?
没有  我以为你不想参加
No. I didn't think you'd wanna do it.
我不想  但是  我只是为孩子们感到遗憾
I don't, but you know, I just feel bad for the kids.
衣柜这行有很多有趣的事情
A lot of interesting stories in the closet biz.
你怎么从来没跟我们讲过
Oh. Why have you never told us any?
好吧  比如曾经有个家伙
Okay. Well, for example, there was this guy...
-有100多顶帽子  -然后呢
- must have had over a hundred hats... - Yes?
我们得想办法把那些帽子都放进衣柜里
And we had to fit them in the closet.
然后呢
Okay?
我们做到了
And we did.
好吧  也许这不是世上最刺激的职业
All right. Maybe it's not the most exciting career in the world,
但这真的很挣钱
but it pays the bills.
没人嫌弃
No one is complaining.
要问我想不想干别的事情  想啊
Were there other things I'd rather do? Yes.
-但我得维持生计  -别的什么事情
- But I had to make ends meet. - What other things?
我一直想写惊悚小说
Well, I always wanted to write thrillers.
-比如那个帽子的故事吗  -间谍惊悚小说
- Like that hat story? - Spy thrillers.
我已经仔细考虑过主角的身份了
I've been kicking around this character,
中情局探员查克·斯通  他毫不在意
CIA agent Chuck Stone, who doesn't care
自己的古怪行为会惹恼阿灵顿的高层们
how much his antics annoy the brass in Arlington.
你为什么不写写看
Why didn't you ever try it?
我一直忙于工作和家庭
I was busy with work and family.
我本打算离婚后开始写
I was gonna start writing after my divorce,
但是被生活琐事妨碍了
But you know... life got in the way.
你说生活琐事的时候为什么指着我
Why do you point at me when you say "Life"?
我是生活琐事吗
Am I "Life"?
我是说你让我忙碌了起来
I meant you keep my busy.
你周日睡了3个小时午觉
You had a 3-hour nap on Sunday.
-我很累  -为什么累
- I was tired. From what?
因为周六睡了两个小时午觉吗
Your 2-hour nap on Saturday?
杰  我跟你在一起5年了
Jay, I've been with you for five years,
可从没听你说过什么写书的事
and I've never heard you mention anything about writing.
我买了台打字机
Hey. I bought a typewriter.
打字机
A typewriter?
你的签售会安排在什么时候
When is your book signing?
1975年吗
1975?
我的小说人物非常可怕
It's a hell of a character.
他们教他如何杀人
They taught him how to kill,
但他从没学过如何去爱
but he never learned to love!
不不不  等等  等等
No, no, no, no, no. Wait, wait. Okay.
爸爸  爸爸  牙仙子来过了
Daddies! Daddies! The tooth fairy came.
-什么  不是吧  -真叫人激动
- What? No way! - Oh, that's so exciting!
她给你带了什么
What'd she bring you?
仙尘啊  真不错
Oh! Fairy dust. Nice touch.
天呐  太多了
Oh, my gosh, it's a lot.
还有贴纸
Some stickers...
一把牙刷
A toothbrush...
还有一张百元大钞
And a hundred dollar bill!
-什么  -快瞧瞧
- What? Okay. - Look at that.
我爱牙仙子
I love the tooth fairy.
牙仙子给我们家女儿100美元呢
The tooth fairy gave our daughter $100.
她不知道一颗牙的市场价格顶多5美元吗
Does she not know that the going rate for a tooth is $5 at the most?
显然  牙仙子搞错了
Well, obviously, the tooth fairy made a mistake.
可能是因为牙仙子
Maybe it's 'cause the tooth fairy
昨晚喝了太多夏敦埃酒
had a little too much chardonnay last night.
我觉得牙仙子能扛得住夏敦埃酒
I think the tooth fairy can handle the chardonnay.
但她恐怕无法接受
What I don't think she can handle
批评别人在漆黑的夜里
is criticizing someone who made an honest mistake
所犯下的无心之过
in the dark of the night.
我要把它放进我的小手包里
I'm gonna put this in my clutch.
我等不及要告诉学校里的每个人了
I can't wait to tell everyone at school!
听着  我们做父母的可不能冒充牙仙
Okay, we cannot be the parents of a 6-year-old
给6岁的女儿一张百元大钞
who gets $100 from the tooth fairy.
我们的孩子才6岁就有手包已经够离谱了
It's bad enough we're the parents of a 6-year-old with a clutch.
那个包从早到晚都可以用
You know, that bag transitions from day to night seamlessly,
而且我不用再在口袋里装蜡笔了
and I no longer have to carry crayons in my front pocket.
不要再争这个了
Can't have this argument again!
安医生  谢谢你
Thank you, Dr. Ann,
向我们展示了真实的心理辅导
for showing us how exciting and surprising
多么令人激动和惊喜
a real live therapy session can be.
我会收好这张名片的
I will hold on to this card.
接下来  有请卢克的爸爸  邓菲先生
Next up, we have Luke's dad, Mr. Dunphy.
谢谢
Hey. Thank you.
你们猜怎么着
Guess what?
你不在家的时候我去过你家
I've been in your house when you weren't home.
还有你家  你家也去过
And yours. And yours.
不  我不是小偷  我是房地产经纪人
No, I'm not a burglar. I'm a realtor.
抱歉我迟到了
Ho! Hey, sorry I'm late!
我刚刚又卖出去一座豪宅
I just sold another mansion.
你好吗  亲爱的
How you doin', honey?
历史充满了激烈的竞争
History is full of great rivalries--
雅典与斯巴达  凯瑞甘与哈丁
Athens and Sparta, Kerrigan and Harding,
菲尔·邓菲和格尔·索普
Phil Dunphy and Gil Thorpe.
现在这种局面  他是汤娅  我是南希
In this scenario, he's the Tonya, I'm the Nancy.
[花样滑冰选手汤娅·哈丁攻击了对手南希·凯瑞甘]
注意了  孩子们
Pay attention, kids.
即将演讲的是镇上排名第4的地产经纪人
You're about to hear from the number four realtor in town.
无论如何  我不打算做无聊的演讲
Anyway, uh, I'm not gonna bore you guys with a lecture.
相反  我想让你们看看
Instead, I'd like you to watch
我和一个年轻人之间的对话
as I converse with a young man
他正在思考自己的人生目标
who's wondering what to do with his life.
孩子你好
Hey, kid.
孩子  看这里  看这里
Hey, kid, up here! Up here!
老兄  什么事
Yo, dude! Whassup?
我来告诉你什么事
I'll tell you what's up.
我想帮助你
I'm interested in helping you
给你讲讲在房地产界打拼的事情
by telling you all about a career in real estate.
房地产  不就是买房子和卖房子吗
Real estate? Isn't that just buying and selling houses?
我没空搞那个  太没用了
I don't have time for that. Epic fail.
看来我们得从头讲起了
Sounds like we need to start at the beginning.
你看  房地产这行的重点就是人
You see, real estate is about people.
人
People?
你说得太对了菲尔  我们这份工作
Couldn't agree more, Phil. Best part of our job
最大的妙处就是让对的人住进对的家
is putting the right person in the right home.
-格尔  -实际上  就在上周
- Gil... - Matter of fact, last week,
我让一对"西班牙"夫妇住进了
I put a "Spanish" Couple into
[美国人把所有拉丁美洲人都叫做西班牙人]
-西班牙式的房子  -格尔
- a Spanish home. - Gil.
一个没有房子的世界  那真是太疯狂了
A world without houses? That's cray cray.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
菲尔对不起  我不是故意搞砸你的表演
Phil, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to screw up your little show.
我知道这种表演把握好时间最重要
I know timing is critical on these things.
-拜托格尔  -相信我  我最不想
- Gil, please. - Believe me, the last thing I want to do is...
7频道天气预报员的房子是你卖给他的吗
You sold a house to the channel 7 weatherman?
不  不是
No. No.
但科比·布莱恩特有套房子是我卖给他的
But I did sell one to Kobe Bryant.
什么  他不是在跟你说话  是跟我
What?! Guess what? He's not talking to you. He's talking to me.
其实我有个很好笑的故事要讲
And I have a very funny story, actually.
-有个人走进...不  -太好笑了
- A guy walks into... No. - That's hilarious.
不  我还没讲呢
No! I haven't told it!
好吧  对了
Okay, um... Oh!
好球  你说得对
Great throw. You were right.
-确实该看我的了  -就看你的了
- It is in my court. - Ball's in your court!
但你们猜怎么着  其实一直都是我
But guess what-- it was me the whole time.
怎样
What?!
快点孩子们  快点
Come on, kids, come on.
鼓起掌来  鼓起来  他尽力了
Give it up! Give it up! He tried.
我想我们都明白你的意思  菲尔
I think we all know what you were going for, Phil.
不过我看到有几个孩子饿了
But I'm lookin' out here, and I'm seeing some hungry kids.
我说对了没  所以我才买了这么多的
Am I right? That's why I brought plenty of...
格尔腌黄瓜
Gil pickles!
谁想来个格尔腌黄瓜
Who wants a Gil pickle?
来吧  我看都有谁
Come on. Let me see 'em.
好的  来吧  来拿吧
All right. Come on. Grab one.
格尔腌黄瓜
Gil pickles.
太有才了
Genius.
比我的菲尔枕套强多了
So much better than my Phil-low cases.
克莱尔都不喜欢
Claire wasn't a fan.
床上有一个他已经足够了
One of him in bed is more than enough.
听到了吗  女士们
Do you hear that, ladies?
好了  点击"发送"键
All right. Just hit "Send."
你刚刚卖出了一幢房子
Hey! You just sold a house!
而那就是你余生要追求的高目标
And you're gonna be chasing that high for the rest of your life.
大家给她鼓鼓掌吧
Give her a round of applause, everybody.
她刚刚卖出了一幢房子
She just sold a house.
孩子们  感谢你们今天请我来
I wanna thank you kids for having me here today.
请记住房地产这一行的三大准则
And remember the three rules of real estate--
索普  索普  索普
Thorpe, Thorpe, Thorpe!
谢谢你  索普先生
Thank you, Mr. Thorpe.
看来我们还剩下一些时间
It turns out we have a little extra time.
-邓菲太太  -怎么了
- Uh, Mrs. Dunphy? - Yes?
同学们一定想听听你的工作
I'm sure the class would love to hear from you.
不  我只是过来给我老公帮忙的
Oh, no. I just came in to help my husband.
我是个全职主妇
I'm a... I'm a stay-at-home mom.
我知道  那也是个很重要的职业
I know. And that's a very important job.
没错  好吧
It is. Uh, yeah.
我可以  我可以讲一讲
I can--I can do this for a minute.
全职主妇
Um, stay-at-home mom.
那就意味着  我实际上
Uh, what that means is I actually have
要做好几项不同的工作
a whole bunch of different jobs.
我既是司机  也是厨师
I am a chauffeur, a chef,
还是管家
Uh, a house manager,
-护士  -这是你小时候的理想吗
- A nurse. - Is it what you always wanted to do?
不  不算吧
No. Not exactly.
我上过大学  学的是市场营销
Uh, I went to college, uh, to study marketing
还在一家大型酒店企业工作过
and worked at one of those big hotel companies.
但自从我有了孩子
But when my kids came along,
我就想在家照顾他们
I just wanted to be there.
给他们擦鼻涕  给他们换尿布
You know, wipe their noses and change their diapers
夜里给他们盖好被子
And tuck 'em in at night.
妈妈
Mom!
郑重声明  我擦什么都是自己擦的
For the record, I do all my own wiping.
那你为什么不重返职场呢
So why haven't you gone back to work?
我最近做了很多事  我整修了一幢房子
I've done a few things lately. I just redid a house,
去年还参选了市政议员
and I ran for city council last year.
你现在是市政议员吗
You're on the city council?
不  我没当上
No. I-I didn't win.
-你输了  -不是说了"没当上"吗
- You lost? - That's what "Didn't win" means.
我本来想等孩子们长大些
I... I thought I would be going back to work
就回去工作
when the kids got older,
不过  这事没有你们想的那么简单
But it--it's not as easy as you might think.
要知道  一个年近40的女人
You know, people aren't exactly lining up
在职场上并不抢手
to hire a woman who's almost 40
何况我都15年没有工作了
and has been out of the job market for 15 years.
我记得你已经42岁了
I thought you were 42.
42和40很接近  卢克
That's almost 40, Luke.
我4岁时我妈妈就回去工作了
My mom went back to work when I was 4.
所以你家才没有人教你不要打断别人说话
Oh, so there was no one at home to teach you not to interrupt?
好了  好了
Okay. Hey, hey, hey!
我来告诉你们吧
Let me tell you something.
全职妈妈们都是英雄
Stay-at-home moms are heroes.
-没错  -她们是这个国家的栋梁
- Yeah. - They're the backbone of this country.
谢了  格尔
Thanks, Gil.
如果非要我做那样的工作
I mean, if I had to do that job,
我大概早把自己喝死了  真的
I'd probably drink myself to death, honestly.
好了  我们给她一些掌声吧
All right, let's give her a round of applause, everybody.
来嘛
Come on.
来嘛  把手拍响点儿  让我听见
Oh, come on, you can do better than that. Let me hear ya!
很好  很好
All right! All right!
好了  下课了  都走吧
All right, class dismissed. Get out of here!
不
No!
不  不  不
No, no, no.
还有  同学们  还有3个小时才结束
We have... Guys, we have three more hours.
-给  -我的旧打字机
- Here. - My old typewriter.
你不是说你想写作吗  写吧
You said you want to write. Write.
现在吗  我今天很忙
Now? I've got a busy day.
我已经给你办公室打过电话了
I already called your office
告诉他们  你今天不会去公司
And told them that you can't come in
乱晃上20分钟
to walk around for 20 minutes
跟每个人说  "怎么样  小子"
saying to everyone, "What's up, sport?"
我明白  你暗含的意思是
I know this is your subtle little way
你觉得我写不出东西
of saying you don't think I can do it.
不  我是让生活琐事为你让路
No. It's life getting out of the way.
好吧  我这就接受你的小小挑战
Fine. I'm gonna take you up on your little challenge,
不过你要知道
but you should know this--
等你人老珠黄那天  你这种行为
this behavior of yours is not gonna fly
就不会得逞了
when you lose your looks.
到那时你都死好久了
You're gonna be long gone by then.
-邓菲  -有事吗
- Dunphy. - Yeah? Oh.
-你还好吗  -我很好  我很好
- You okay? - I'm fine. I'm fine.
别因为那个自作聪明的小屁孩烦心
Don't let that little smart-ass bother you, all right.
你见过她妈妈没有  人老珠黄憔悴损
Have you seen her mother? Does not age well.
谢谢你帮我解围
well, um, thanks for rescuing me in there.
顺便帮我跟菲尔说声抱歉吧
And tell Phil I'm sorry
我刚刚可能让他难堪了
if I threw him off in there.
我真是应该学着管好自己的大嘴巴
I probably should learn just to keep my big blowhole shut.
其实那已经比他排练时好很多了
Actually, it went a little better than it did in rehearsal,
说真的
to be honest.
-不过我会向他转达  -好
- But I will tell him what you said. - All right.
你刚才略为抓狂的表现让我想起些事情
You know, your little meltdown in there got me thinking.
我正在开发一处零售和办公区
I'm building a retail office development,
因此我需要有人
and I could use a liaison
负责联络规划委员会
to work with the planning commission.
你是要雇用我吗
Are you offering me a job?
是的  你认识市政厅的人
Well, yeah. You know people in city hall,
而且你炒房也炒得很不错
and you did a hell of a job on that flip.
为了你和你家人的安全
And for the safety of you and your family,
我得让你从家里出来
I gotta get you out of that house.
可你和菲尔是竞争对手
But you and Phil are competitors. It--
这事没竞争
Not on this.
听我说  这事要成了  对大家都好
Look, if this works out, everybody's gonna win...
除了我们要赶走的那家热带鱼店
Except for that tropical fish store we're booting out of there.
我对此一点罪恶感都没有
I don't feel bad about that at all.
你能让我回去想几天吗
Can I take a couple of days to think about it?
-没问题  慢慢想  不着急  -好
- Yeah. Yeah. Take your time. No pressure. - Okay.
你想好了  就给我个电话
And when you're ready, just give me a call.
-好的  -木棒上有我电话
- Okay. - Number's on the stick.
好的  格尔腌黄瓜
Great. Oh, yeah. Okay. Gil pickle.
回见  索普  索普  索普
See ya! Thorpe! Thorpe! Thorpe!
索普  索普  索普
Thorpe. Thorpe. Thorpe.
猜我在信箱里发现了什么
Look what just came in the mail--
莉莉  是寄给你的信
A letter addressed to you, Lily.
是吗  很少有人寄信给我
Really? I don't get much mail.
我们看看
Oh, let's see here.
是牙仙子寄来的
Uh, yeah. Oh, the tooth fairy.
牙达科他州  牙市 牙仙子街1号
"1 Tooth Fairy Lane. Tooth City, Tooth Dakota."
希望她又送我100美元
I hope it's another $100.
我们看看是什么
Ooh! Well, lookie there.
金粉闪闪啊
Glitter!
估计这牙仙子从来不用扫地吧
I guess the tooth fairy doesn't have to worry about vacuuming.
亲爱的莉莉  我来信是因为我犯了错
See, "Dear Lily, I'm writing because I made a mistake"
给了你太多的钱
"and gave you too much money."
请你今晚把那100美元放在枕头下
"Please leave the $100 under your pillow tonight,"
我会给你1美元
"and I'll give you a dollar.
抱歉让你伤心了[咬到你]
Sorry if that bites."
让我看看
Let me see that.
我不识字
I can't read.
听起来她真的很烦恼
Uh, well, it sounds like she's really in a jam.
我觉得  我们必须
And I think we're gonna
把那100美元还给牙仙子
have to give the tooth fairy her $100 back.
不行  我想留着
No! I wanna keep it.
想到要靠她给我们养老
I'm scared that she's gonna be the one
-就觉得好可怕  -是啊
- taking care of us when we're older. - Yeah.
查克·斯通
"Chuck Stone,"
身高6英尺  火眼晶晶坚韧不拔的硬汉
"6-foot, 3-inches of steely eyed determination"
坐在审讯桌前
"sat at the interrogation table."
他的脑海一片空白
"His mind was a blank..."
空空如也
"A complete blank.
他一件实在的事情都想不出来
"He literally could not think of one single, solitary thing.
这时  他发现了一块污渍
"Then he noticed a spot."
像是早餐时滴落的糖浆
"It looked like syrup left over from breakfast..."
这让他想起来  该吃午饭了
"Which made him realize it was lunchtime."
他吃了块培根生菜番茄三明治
"A bacon, lettuce, and tomato, sandwich--"
查克·斯通管它叫"培生番"
"Or B.L.T, as Chuck Stone called it--
这顿饭正和他胃口
"would really hit the spot."
查克发现  这美味的诀窍在于蛋黄酱
"The secret, chuck realized, was real mayonnaise..."
而不是他老婆平时买给儿子的健康食品
"Not that healthy crap his wife kept buying for their son."
该死的
Damn it!
一大串T到底是什么意思
"I mean, what's the point of t-t-t-t-t-t-t?"
你和我  共饮茶
"Tea for two. Two for tea."
之后写的就更加不堪入目了
It only gets worse from here.
你开什么玩笑
You can't be serious!
格尔·索普是我的死对头
Gil Thorpe is my nemesis!
菲尔  我不想打击你
I hate to break it to you, Phil,
但你不是蝙蝠侠
but you're not Batman.
相信我
Trust me.
格尔非常阴险  他是利用你来对付我
Gil's a snake and he's found the perfect way to mess with me.
你就从来没想过也许他想雇我是因为
Did it ever occur to you that he was hiring me because of...
不知道  我很能干
I don't know? Me.
你开什么玩笑  你到底是谁的老婆
Are you kidding? What's your last name?!
现在还真难说
Right now?
对不起  克莱尔
I'm sorry, Claire.
我也不想  但我要行使我的否决权
I-I hate to do this, but I have to use my veto.
否决权  你才没有什么否决权
Veto? Oh, you don't get any vetoes.
你总是否决我
You veto me all the time.
因为你的想法都太蠢了
'Cause you have dumb ideas.
你倒是举个例子听听
Name one.
她说了好久
That went on for a while.
还有在浴室里存零食的主意
...And let's not forget shower snacks.
不可能只有我会洗澡洗得肚子饿
I can't be the only one who gets hungry in there!
杰  我妈说你在写书
Hey, Jay. My mom said you were writing a book.
真是帅呆了啊
That's fantastic.
顺便提一句  今天的职业日有点奇怪
By the way, Career Day was a little weird.
我觉得克莱尔最近心情不好
I think Claire's going through some pretty dark stuff,
-你也许该去关心一下  -别闲聊了
- and you might want to check... - Enough chitchat.
我正想办法让我的主角走出困境呢
I've gotta get a character out of a bind.
他怎么了
Ooh. What did he do?
他跟他老婆说  他能写本书
He told his wife he could write a book.
别放弃  杰  自我怀疑是个必经过程
Don't give up, Jay. Self-doubt is part of the process.
如果你不自我批判
You can't be a good writer
你就成不了一个好作家
without being critical of your own work.
怎么了
What?
我实在想不出好话来鼓励你
I'm racking my brain for a compliment here.
我知道  写得烂透了
I know. It stinks.
这回要让你妈看笑话了
And your mom's gonna rub it in my face pretty good.
好  查克·斯通为什么要审问这个人
Okay. Why is Chuck Stone interrogating this guy?
他需要知道密码  否则的话
He needs the codes. If he doesn't get 'em,
国际空间站就会
the International Space Station's gonna
在除夕夜坠落在时代广场
crash into Times Square on New Year's Eve.
所以他时间无多了
So he's short of time.
他只剩两分钟  他走投无路了
He's got about two minutes. He's desperate.
这样如何
How about this?
查克·斯通笑了笑  点燃一支烟
"Chuck Stone smiled and lit a cigarette,"
仿佛他还有大把的时间
"as if he had all the time in the world,"
然而其实  地球快要毁灭了
when in fact, the world was about to end."
精彩啊  然后呢然后呢
Holy crap. What happens next?
你让开  我来写
Move over. I'll type.
给我来点咖啡吧  谢谢
Some coffee would be great. Thanks.
抱歉  但我不明白为什么
I'm sorry. I don't understand why
我们不能直接走进去
we don't just go in there,
告诉她我们要把钱拿走  就完事了
we tell her we're taking the money, and that's that.
因为这是个教育孩子的机会
Because this is a teaching moment,
我们得引导她自愿把钱交出来
and we want her to want to give the money back.
我只是非常担心
I'm just really worried
我们要成为过分放纵孩子的家长了
we're becoming those overindulgent parents right now.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
好  牙仙子  你准备好了吗
Okay, you ready, tooth fairy?
-行动吧  -好吧
- Let's do this. - All right.
莉莉  看谁来了
Lily, look who came to say hi!
是我  牙仙子
It's me, the tooth fairy.
我来是想请你帮个忙
And I've come to ask you for a favor!
你真的是牙仙子吗
Are you really the tooth fairy?
是的  看我的翅膀
Oh, yes, I am. Look at my wings!
你会飞吗  我想看你飞
Can you fly? I wanna see you fly.
我现在飞不了  因为...
Well, I can't right now because...
因为...
Well, because--
因为牙仙子太伤心了
Because the tooth fairy's too sad to fly...
因为她犯了错  只有你能帮她解决
Because she made a mistake that only you can make better.
又是因为那钱吗
Is this about the money again?
是的  没错
Well, yes, it is.
我还得留着钱给别的小盆友呢
I need enough for all the other children's tooths.
-小朋友  -慢着
- Teeth. - Wait a minute.
你不是牙仙子  你是海莉
You're not the tooth fairy. You're Haley.
不  我是牙仙子
No! I am the tooth fairy!
看  我有仙女金粉
Look! Fairy dust!
金粉又得辛苦我扫地了
And there's that glitter.
你们为什么撒谎
Why did you lie?
你们说过撒谎是不对的
You said lying was wrong.
我们也说过  要帮助遇到困难的人
We also said that when someone is in trouble, you help them.
我怎么知道你们不是在骗我
How do I know you weren't lying?
她太聪明了
She is good.
好吧莉莉  不胡闹了
All right, Lily, this is ridiculous.
牙仙子犯了个错
All right, the tooth fairy has made a mistake.
你必须把那100美元放到枕头下
You need to put the $100 under the pillow,
就这样  没得商量
and that is the end of the story.
因为你觉得这样做是对的
Because you believe it's the right thing to do...
-没错  -对吧
- Yes. - Don't you?
可是我想买滑板车
But I wanna buy a scooter.
换我也会这么做
Oh. That's what I'd do.
我是说
I mean...
管他圣诞老人怎么想呢
Who cares what Santa thinks, right?
圣诞老人
Santa?
对啊  他全都看在眼里
Well, he sees everything,
这事恐怕会让他把你放进坏孩子名单
And this'll probably put you on the "Naughty" list.
可你根本不必每年等他来给你送礼物
But who needs presents every year?
因为你自己都有100美元了
You've got a hundred dollars.
你可以骑着滑板车在空空的圣诞树下
You can ride around that empty christmas tree
晃悠到变成老太太为止
until you're an old lady.
可以给我些时间考虑下吗
Can I have some time to think about it?
-你不需要时间  -当然可以  宝贝
- You don't need any... - Of course, sweetie.
好的
Yeah. Okay.
海莉  这招太高了
Haley? Okay, that was brilliant.
多谢  这身行头可以借我吗
Thanks. Oh, also, can I borrow this?
-为什么  -我还是不说的好
- Why? - I'd rather not say.
我戴上假发后
You know, after I put on the wig,
可以感觉到融入角色了
I just... I felt like the character.
等等
Hang on.
侬好哇
Yell-o?
问一下  这是真正的菲尔还是视频菲尔
Quick question. Am I talking to live Phil or video Phil?
你想干嘛  格尔
What do you want, Gil?
只想确定下你不介意你老婆叫我"大老板"
I just wanna make sure it's okay that your wife calls me "Boss."
-再见  -慢着  别挂
- Good-bye. - Oh, hold on! Hold on!
我逗你玩儿呢
I'm just messing with ya.
但我的确认为
Although I do think
你老婆会很享受在我"下面"办事
your wife's gonna enjoy being under me.
我儿子在车里
My son is in the car.
大明星  还好吗
Hey, superstar! What's up?
听着  任何时候你想来海边别墅
Listen, any time you wanna swing by the beach house,
我都很乐意教你如何扔橄榄回旋球
I'll be glad to show you how to throw a tight spiral
就像我当年在德州理工那样  好耶
like I did at Texas Tech. Booyah!
-汤米  -他已经会扔了
- Tommy! - He already knows how to throw.
-我的同志舅夫小卡教我了  -让我来
- Yeah, my gay uncle Cam taught me. - I-I got this.
这是我们的恩怨  不能把家人扯进来
This was between us. You don't bring family into it.
让克莱尔空欢喜一场  你真是卑鄙
Low blow getting Claire's hopes up.
我没有让她空欢喜一场
Hey, I'm not getting her hopes up.
这是有着真正好处的真正工作
This is a real job with real bennies--
其中一项好处就是
One of which is
任何时候她俯身在我桌前
I get to tell you what I'm thinking
我都可以告诉你我的想法
whenever she leans over my desk!
这下我真是要开心死了
Oh, I'm gonna have so much fun with this!
回见了  小邓邓
Later, Dunph-bags!
真是个混蛋
What a jerk.
知道吗  得在你妈妈
You know what? We're gonna tell your mom
答应与他合作前  告诉她
before she goes into business with this guy.
他真是"格"犹如"索普在背"的烦人精
He's Gil-ty of being a Thorpe in my side.
[原词为Thorn in my side: 芒刺在背]
太刻意了
Trying too hard.
是的
Yeah.
我回来了
Hello!
闪一边去
Move!
你没事
You're fine.
怎么样
So?
第一天写作如何啊
How was your first day of writing?
歌洛莉亚  安静  让我写完最后一句
Gloria, shh! Let me finish one thought.
好了
Got it.
你真的写出了东西吗
So you actually wrote something?
开始比较不顺
Well, it was slow going at first,
然后就文思如泉涌了
but then the juices started flowing.
-我能看看吗  -当然
- May I? - Sure.
如果有帮助的话  把主角意淫成汤姆·贝伦杰
Uh, if it helps, picture Tom Berenger.
[演员  代表作为电影《野战排》]
我总是意淫着别人
I always do.
怎么了
What?
只是
Well, it's just this...
第一句有点长啊
This first sentence is a bit long.
是长还是生动形象
Long or dynamic?
又长又令人迷惑  我分不清是谁在说话
No, long and confusing. I can't tell who's talking.
也许这是模仿《战争迷雾》
Maybe that's just to mimic The Fog of Battle.
[电影原名为The Fog of War]
好吧
Okay.
又怎么了
What now?
只是  1965年时没有手机
Just... There were no cell phones in 1965.
那是个错误  我会改的
That's a mistake. I'm changing that.
不能改  结尾又会出现
You can't change that. It comes back in the end...
我猜想的
I-I presume.
重点是  我可以写作
The point is, I can write.
我可能不会以此为业
I probably won't pursue it,
但这是可行的职业选择
but it's a viable career option.
中情局有着各种顶级机密的高科技
The CIA had all sorts of top-secret technology.
你怎么知道他们当时没有手机
Who's to say they didn't have cell phones?
曼尼  算了
Manny, let it go.
这个查克·斯通
And this Chuck Stone--
似乎不太擅长他的工作啊
He doesn't seem very good at his job.
他有缺点  这样角色才会有趣
He's flawed. That's what makes the character interesting.
如果你要完美的  用机器人好了
If you want someone perfect, put in a robot.
机器人
A robot!
我喜欢机器人
I like a robot.
不  我的故事中不能有机器人
No! You're not putting a robot in my story!
没错  这是我写的
That's right, my story.
你肯定开心死了
You must be very happy.
我本该开心的  但生活妨碍了我开心
I would be, but life got in the way.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
找出了我以前的公文包
Oh, I just got out my old briefcase.
还是可以重返职场的
It's still capable of doing the job,
和我一样
Just like me.
克莱尔  有些事你得知道
Claire, you have to understand something.
有些事你得知道
You have to understand something.
我整天都沉浸在幸福之中
I walked around all day on cloud nine
因为有人赏识我的价值
because somebody valued me.
我赏识你的价值  我们都如此
I value you. We all value you.
你们当然赏识
No, of course you do,
因为我做饭  打扫  收拾脏内衣
Because I cook and I clean and I pick up dirty underwear.
亲爱的  这个不一样
No, honey, it's different than that.
我已经做旁观者很多年了
I have been on the sidelines for so long,
我不知道是否还会有人认为
I didn't know if anybody would ever think
我有能力重新工作
I have what it takes again.
我知道格尔不是什么好人
I know Gil's not the greatest guy,
但这很重要  我想
But this is important. And I think--
我想你应该接受这份工作
I think you should take the job.
但是  爸
But, dad...
不  卢克  你妈说得对
No, Luke. She's right.
她会非常出色的
Your mom's gonna be amazing at this.
-我收回否决权  -你从未有过否决权
- I retract my veto. - You never had a veto.
-我有  -你没有  我告诉你为什么
- Yes, I did. - No, you didn't, and I'll tell you why.
她又说了好久
And that went on for a while.
最后  这番对话就会发生在
...And lastly, this whole conversation would be happening
-圆顶帐篷中  -那是完美的结构
- in a yurt. - It's the perfect structure.
我得把旧西装里的垫肩都拿掉
I have to go take the shoulder pads out of all my old suits!
你知道他会继续取笑你吧
You know he's gonna keep teasing you.
只要你妈妈开心  我能承受几个电话
If it makes your mom happy, I can handle a few phone calls.
还有短信
And texts.
-说了什么  -没什么我不能承受的
- What does it say? - Nothing I can't handle.
"我们都在编织着谎言之网
"We all weave a web of lies."
有些谎言  是为了帮助所爱的人
"Some we tell to try to help the ones we love."
有些谎言  是为了欺骗自己"
"Some we tell to try to fool ourselves."
"有些谎言  是因为
"And some we tell because,
当子弹用尽
when you're out of bullets
凝视着冲锋枪的枪管时
and staring down the barrel of a kalashnikov,
剩下的武器只有  诡计"
the only weapon you've got left is guile."
你妈妈太不识货了  这棒极了
She's nuts. That's fantastic.
孩子们  快过来
Okay, guys, bring it in!
在妈妈回家前  我们要把家里收拾干净
Let's get this place shipshape before she gets home.
我肯定她第一天上班很辛苦
I'm sure she had a big first day.
海莉  你负责洗衣服
Haley, I'm putting you on laundry.
艾丽克斯  收拾厨房与吸尘
Alex, kitchen and vacuum.
卢克  你清洁厕所
Luke, you're cleaning the bathroom.
为什么是我
Why me?
因为弄脏的人总是你
Because you always mess it up.
你为什么不能尿在马桶里呢
Yeah, why can't you pee straight?
站得那么远  我已经很不错了
Hey, I'm doing a great job from that far back.
好了孩子们  邓菲队数到三加油
Okay, guys, team Dunphy on three.
一  二  对了  有许多事要做
One, two--that's right, we got a lot to do!
亲爱的  你怎么这么早就回来了
Honey, what are you doing home so early?
我辞职了  那家伙是头彻头彻尾的猪
I quit. That man is a complete pig.
他把我当仆人一样使唤
He treated me like a servant
完全不尊重我
and showed me absolutely no respect.
太遗憾了  你不该受到那样的待遇
I'm so sorry. You deserve better than that.
的确是
I do.
晚饭吃什么
So what's for dinner?
你是不是听错了  我是说你晚饭想吃什么
I feel like you heard me wrong. I said, what's for dinner?
我听得很清楚
I heard you!